Guide to the Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York Records 1785-2014 MS 2997
New-York Historical Society
Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York records
1785-2014
New-York Historical Society
Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York
MS 2997
118 Linear feet
The collection contains records (1785-2014) of the Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York, a Scottish-American charitable and social organization. The records document the organization's administrative history, membership, charitable efforts, and cultural events.
Biographical/Historical Note
The Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York was founded in 1756 to provide charitable relief and promote social ties within the growing Scottish-American community. It followed the founding of Saint Andrew's Societies in Charleston (1729), Philadelphia (1747), and Savannah (1750), as well as the Scots Society of New-York (1744-1753). In 1775, meetings were suspended due to the Revolutionary War. At that time the Society's membership included both British officers and American revolutionaries. Three members—Philip Lawrence, Lewis Morris, and John Witherspoon—were signers of the Declaration of Independence. In 1784 the Society reorganized and resumed its original mission. There are few records from this early period, however, because in 1835, most documents, including the original constitution signed by the founding members, were lost in a fire.
The Society's membership was initially open only to Scottish men and their sons and grandsons. In 1897, membership was opened to men of any Scottish lineal descent. The membership of the society involved many political, commercial, and cultural leaders. During the Civil War, a number of members served in the 79th New York Volunteer Infantry, nicknamed the Highland Guard. Other prominent members include: Philip Livingston, William Livingston, Robert R. Livingston, Alexander Hamilton, John Loudon McAdam, Washington Irving, Andrew Carnegie, James Gordon Bennett, Alexander Graham Bell, John Lindsay, and Thomas J. Watson Jr.
Scope and Contents Note
The Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York Records document several significant aspects of Scottish and American history in New York. As a social club that attracted prominent individuals to its leadership and events, and as an aid organization that served Scots in need, the Society produced records that reflect the lives of a wide variety of people within the New York area's Scottish community.
The records contain many types of material, including minutes, financial ledgers, committee records, and ephemera.
The collection is arranged in the following six series:
Series I: Administrative Records
Series II: Charitable Records
Series III: Membership Records
Series IV: Event Records
Series V: The Pibroch
Series VI: Miscellaneous Historical Material
A more detailed description of the contents of each series is included in the container list.
Immediate Source of Acquisition Note
Gift of Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York, 2015
Access Restrictions
Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Records related to almoners and to members are restricted from access for 35 years; that restriction is noted within the finding aid at the relevant series or subseries level.
Related Materials Note
The Printed Collections of the New-York Historical Society hold a collection of material related to Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York under the call number F128 HS2725 .S14.
There is also a small amount of oversize archival material, separate from this collection, at the New-York Historical Society labeled: Y-Saint Andrew's Society.
Account books.; Ephemera.; Letters (correspondence); Photographs.; Records (documents).; Registers (lists); Charities -- New York (State) -- New York.; Clubs -- New York (State) -- New York.; Scottish Americans -- New York (State); New York (State) -- Social life and customs.; Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York -- Archives.
- Series I: Administrative Records, 1785-2008
  Scope and Contents Note
  This series contains material related to the operations and management of the Society as a whole. It is arranged into subseries that detail the organization's institutional structure, which includes an early treasurer's book, minutes, reports, printed histories, committee records, and office files.
  - Subseries I.1: Treasurer's Book, 1785-1860 (Offsite-box SA-1, Volume 1)
    The treasurer's book is a manuscript general ledger documenting the society's income and expenses from 1785 to 1860. Treasurer's records for the period after 1860 exist within the subseries Minutes and Annual Reports.
    - Treasurer's Book, 1785 - 1860 (Offsite-box SA-1, Volume 1)
  - Subseries I.2: Minutes, 1835-1990
    Scope and Contents
    Minutes (1835 - 1989) provide an account of the Society's activities and include information related to charitable giving, membership, constitutional changes, and other facets of the organization's operation. Bound minutes are in some cases supplemented, or in later years, replaced by foldered material that includes correspondence, agendas, copies of reports, and the minutes themselves.
    General Meeting minutes (1835- 1990) record the larger meetings called by the President to elect officers, receive annual reports, form committees, and otherwise express the intentions of the Society as a whole. These include Annual, Semi-Annual, Preparatory, and various Special Meetings. Bound minutes exist from 1835 to 1960. Foldered material runs from 1950 to 1990.
    Minutes of the Board of Managers (1884 - 1989) record monthly meetings that address changes in membership, review monthly financial and charity reports, and attend to other business as needed. Bound volumes cover the period from 1884 to 1966. Foldered material exists from 1953 to 1989.
    Some of what is contained in General Meeting minutes in relation to reports and officers can also be found in the subseries Annual Reports. Likewise, information related to the membership of individuals in the Society can also be found in the series Membership.
    Arrangement Note
    General Meeting minutes are arranged first, followed by Board of Managers' Meeting minutes. Each set of minutes is ordered chronologically.
    - General Meetings, 1835 September 16 - 1866 November 30 (Offsite-box SA-1, Volume 2)
    - General Meetings, 1867 August 8 - 1893 November 9 (Offsite-box SA-1, Volume 3)
    - General Meetings, 1893 December 1 - 1899 May 4 (Offsite-box SA-1, Volume 4)
    - General Meetings, 1895 March 5 - 1899 November 10 (Offsite-box SA-1, Volume 5)
    - General Meetings, 1900 March 22 - 1904 November 3 (Offsite-box SA-1, Volume 6)
    - General Meetings, 1905 May 4 - 1909 November 4 (Offsite-box SA-1, Volume 7)
    - General Meetings, 1910 May 5 - 1914 November 5 (Offsite-box SA-2, Volume 8)
    - General Meetings, 1915 May 6 - 1919 November 19 (Offsite-box SA-2, Volume 9)
    - General Meetings, 1920 May 6 - 1925 October 16 (Offsite-box SA-2, Volume 10)
    - General Meetings, 1925 November 5 - 1928 October 11 (Offsite-box SA-2, Volume 11)
    - General Meetings, 1928 November 1 - 1931 October 31 (Offsite-box SA-3, Volume 12)
    - General Meetings, 1931 November 5 - 1936 May 7 (Offsite-box SA-3, Volume 13)
    - General Meetings, 1936 October 5 - 1942 February 2 (Offsite-box SA-3, Volume 14)
    - General Meetings, 1943 January 13 - 1955 May 2 (Offsite-box SA-3, Volume 15)
    - General Meetings, 1955 November 10 - 1960 November 10 (Offsite-box SA-4, Volume 16)
    - General Meetings, 1950 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
    - General Meetings, 1953 - 1954 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
    - General Meetings, 1955 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
    - General Meetings, 1956 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
    - General Meetings, 1957 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    - General Meetings, 1958 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
    - General Meetings, 1959 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
    - General Meetings, 1960 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
    - General Meetings, 1961 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
    - General Meetings, 1962 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 10)
    - General Meetings, 1963 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 11)
    - General Meetings, 1964 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
    - General Meetings, 1965 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
    - General Meetings, 1966 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 3)
    - General Meetings, 1967 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 4)
    - General Meetings, 1968 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 5)
    - General Meetings, 1969 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 6)
    - General Meetings, 1970 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 7)
    - General Meetings, 1971 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 8)
    - General Meetings, 1972 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9)
    - General Meetings, 1973 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 10)
    - General Meetings, 1974 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 1)
    - General Meetings, 1975 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 2)
    - General Meetings, 1976 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 3)
    - General Meetings, 1977 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 4)
    - General Meetings, 1978 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 5)
    - General Meetings, 1979 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 6)
    - General Meetings, 1980 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 7)
    - General Meetings, 1981 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 8)
    - General Meetings, 1982 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 9)
    - General Meetings, 1983 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 1)
    - General Meetings, 1984 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 2)
    - General Meetings, 1985 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 3)
    - General Meetings, 1986 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 4)
    - General Meetings, 1987 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 5)
    - General Meetings, 1888 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 6)
    - General Meetings, 1989 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 7)
    - General Meetings, 1990 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 8)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1884 January 3 - 1904 November 3 (Offsite-box SA-4, Volume 17)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1904 November 11 - 1909 December 9 (Offsite-box SA-4, Volume 18)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1910 January 6 - 1914 December 3 (Offsite-box SA-4, Volume 19)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1915 January 7 - 1919 December 4 (Offsite-box SA-4, Volume 20)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1920 January 9 - 1925 December 3 (Offsite-box SA-5, Volume 21)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1926 January 7 - 1930 October 2 (Offsite-box SA-5, Volume 22)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1930 November 6 - 1935 October 3 (Offsite-box SA-5, Volume 23)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1935 November 7 - 1940 October 3 (Offsite-box SA-5, Volume 24)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1940 November 7 - 1945 October 4 (Offsite-box SA-5, Volume 25)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1945 November 8 - 1952 June 5 (Offsite-box SA-5, Volume 26)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1952 October 9 - 1957 December 5 (Offsite-box SA-6, Volume 27)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1958 January 9 - 1962 December 6 (Offsite-box SA-6, Volume 28)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1963 January 10 - 1966 October 6 (Offsite-box SA-6, Volume 29)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1953 March - December (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1954 January - June (Offsite-box 4, Folder 10)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1954 August - December (Offsite-box 4, Folder 11)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1955 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 12)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1956 January - June (Offsite-box 4, Folder 13)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1956 August - October (Offsite-box 5, Folder 1)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1956 November - December (Offsite-box 5, Folder 2)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1957 January - April (Offsite-box 5, Folder 3)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1957 May - September (Offsite-box 5, Folder 4)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1957 October - December (Offsite-box 5, Folder 5)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1958 January - April (Offsite-box 5, Folder 6)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1958 May - September (Offsite-box 5, Folder 7)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1958 October - December (Offsite-box 5, Folder 8)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1959 January - April (Offsite-box 5, Folder 9)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1959 May - August (Offsite-box 5, Folder 10)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1959 September - December (Offsite-box 5, Folder 11)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1960 January - June (Offsite-box 5, Folder 12)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1960 July - December (Offsite-box 5, Folder 13)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1961 January - June (Offsite-box 5, Folder 14)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1961 July - December (Offsite-box 5, Folder 15)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1962 January - June (Offsite-box 5, Folder 16)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1962 July - December (Offsite-box 5, Folder 17)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1963 January - June (Offsite-box 6, Folder 1)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1963 July - December 1963 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 2)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1964 January - April (Offsite-box 6, Folder 3)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1964 May - August (Offsite-box 6, Folder 4)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1964 September - December (Offsite-box 6, Folder 5)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1965 January - April (Offsite-box 6, Folder 6)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1965 May - August (Offsite-box 6, Folder 7)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1965 September - December (Offsite-box 6, Folder 8)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1966 January - April (Offsite-box 6, Folder 9)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1966 May - August (Offsite-box 6, Folder 10)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1966 September - December (Offsite-box 6, Folder 11)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1967 January - April (Offsite-box 6, Folder 12)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1967 May - August (Offsite-box 6, Folder 13)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1967 September - December (Offsite-box 7, Folder 1)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1968 January - May (Offsite-box 7, Folder 2)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1968 June - October (Offsite-box 7, Folder 3)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1968 November - December (Offsite-box 7, Folder 4)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1969 January - April (Offsite-box 7, Folder 5)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1969 May - September (Offsite-box 7, Folder 6)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1969 October - December (Offsite-box 7, Folder 7)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1970 January (Offsite-box 7, Folder 8)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1970 February (Offsite-box 7, Folder 9)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1970 March - July (Offsite-box 7, Folder 10)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1970 August - December (Offsite-box 7, Folder 11)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1971 January - April (Offsite-box 8, Folder 1)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1971 May - July (Offsite-box 8, Folder 2)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1971 August - December (Offsite-box 8, Folder 3)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1972 January - March (Offsite-box 8, Folder 4)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1972 April - June (Offsite-box 8, Folder 5)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1972 July - September (Offsite-box 8, Folder 6)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1972 October - December (Offsite-box 8, Folder 7)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1973 January - March (Offsite-box 8, Folder 8)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1973 April - June (Offsite-box 8, Folder 9)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1973 July - September (Offsite-box 8, Folder 10)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1973 October - December (Offsite-box 8, Folder 11)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1974 January - March (Offsite-box 8, Folder 12)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1974 April - June (Offsite-box 9, Folder 1)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1974 July - September (Offsite-box 9, Folder 2)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1974 October - December (Offsite-box 9, Folder 3)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1975 January - March (Offsite-box 9, Folder 4)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1975 April - June (Offsite-box 9, Folder 5)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1975 July - September (Offsite-box 9, Folder 6)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1975 October - December (Offsite-box 9, Folder 7)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1976 January - March (Offsite-box 9, Folder 8)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1976 April - June (Offsite-box 9, Folder 9)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1976 July - September (Offsite-box 9, Folder 10)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1976 October - December (Offsite-box 9, Folder 11)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1977 January - March (Offsite-box 9, Folder 12)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1977 April - June (Offsite-box 9, Folder 13)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1977 July - September (Offsite-box 9, Folder 14)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1977 October - December (Offsite-box 9, Folder 15)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1978 January - March (Offsite-box 9, Folder 16)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1978 April - June (Offsite-box 9, Folder 17)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1978 July - September (Offsite-box 10, Folder 1)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1978 October - December (Offsite-box 10, Folder 2)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1979 January - March (Offsite-box 10, Folder 3)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1979 April - June (Offsite-box 10, Folder 4)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1979 July - September (Offsite-box 10, Folder 5)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1979 October - December (Offsite-box 10, Folder 6)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1980 January - February (Offsite-box 10, Folder 7)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1980 March - April (Offsite-box 10, Folder 8)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1980 May - June (Offsite-box 10, Folder 9)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1980 July - August (Offsite-box 10, Folder 10)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1980 September - October (Offsite-box 10, Folder 11)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1980 November - December (Offsite-box 10, Folder 12)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1981 January - February (Offsite-box 11, Folder 1)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1981 March - April (Offsite-box 11, Folder 2)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1981 May - June (Offsite-box 11, Folder 3)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1981 October (Offsite-box 11, Folder 4)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1981 November - December (Offsite-box 11, Folder 5)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1982 January - February (Offsite-box 11, Folder 6)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1982 March - April (Offsite-box 11, Folder 7)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1982 May - June (Offsite-box 11, Folder 8)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1982 October - November (Offsite-box 11, Folder 9)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1982 December (Offsite-box 11, Folder 10)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1985 May - June (Offsite-box 12, Folder 1)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1985 September - October (Offsite-box 12, Folder 2)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1985 November - December (Offsite-box 12, Folder 3)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1986 January - March (Offsite-box 12, Folder 4)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1986 April - June (Offsite-box 12, Folder 5)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1986 September - October (Offsite-box 12, Folder 6)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1986 November - December (Offsite-box 12, Folder 7)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1987 January - March (Offsite-box 12, Folder 8)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1987 April - June (Offsite-box 12, Folder 9)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1987 July - October (Offsite-box 12, Folder 10)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1987 November - December (Offsite-box 12, Folder 11)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1988 January - March (Offsite-box 12, Folder 12)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1988 April - June (Offsite-box 12, Folder 13)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1988 September - December (Offsite-box 12, Folder 14)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1989 January - March (Offsite-box 12, Folder 15)
    - Board of Managers' Meetings, 1989 April - May (Offsite-box 12, Folder 16)
  - Subseries I.3: Annual Reports, 1835, 1873-1989
    Annual reports published by the Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York contain summaries of activity which may include: lists of officers and committees; financial statements; reports from Secretaries, Almoners, various committees, and other officers; lists of active members; "in memoriam" notices; and the organization's constitution.
    Annual reports from the years 1873 to 1976 are bound in hardcover volumes. Duplicate paperback volumes are housed separately.
    - Annual Report, 1835 (Offsite-box SA-6, Volume 30)
    - Annual Reports, 1873 – 1895 (Offsite-box SA-6, Volume 31)
    - Annual Reports, 1896 – 1907 (Offsite-box SA-6, Volume 32)
    - Annual Reports, 1908 – 1915 (Offsite-box SA-7, Volume 33)
    - Annual Reports, 1916 – 1921 (Offsite-box SA-7, Volume 34)
    - Annual Reports, 1922 – 1927 (Offsite-box SA-7, Volume 35)
    - Annual Reports, 1924 – 1925 (Offsite-box SA-7, Volume 36)
    - Annual Reports, 1928 – 1933 (Offsite-box SA-7, Volume 37)
    - Annual Reports, 1934 – 1939 (Offsite-box SA-7, Volume 38)
    - Annual Reports, 1940 - 1945 (Offsite-box SA-7, Volume 39)
    - Annual Reports, 1946 – 1951 (Offsite-box SA-7, Volume 40)
    - Annual Reports, 1952 – 1955 (Offsite-box SA-7, Volume 41)
    - Annual Reports, 1956 – 1962 (Offsite-box SA-7, Volume 42)
    - Annual Reports, 1963 – 1969 (Offsite-box SA-7, Volume 43)
    - Annual Reports, 1970 – 1976 (Offsite-box SA-8, Volume 44)
    - Annual Report, 1986 (Offsite-box SA-8, Volume 45)
    - Annual Report, 1987 (Offsite-box SA-8, Volume 46)
    - Annual Report, 1989 (Offsite-box SA-8, Volume 47)
    - Duplicate annual reports, 1835 - 1989 (Offsite-box 96)
  - Subseries I.4: Notices, 1835-1989
    Brief printed notices contain lists of officers, reports of the Secretary, meeting schedules, statements regarding dues, and other announcements. They are arranged chronologically.
    - Lists of officers and reports of the Secretary, 1835 - 1873 (Offsite-box SA-8, Volume 49)
    - Lists of officers and reports of the Secretary, 1838 - 1873 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 1)
    - Special meeting announcement regarding death of Abraham Lincoln, 1865 April 17 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 1)
    - List of officers from 1756 to 1937, 1930 - 1937 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 2)
    - Directories for Board of Managers, 1935, 1938, 1942 - 1949 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 3)
    - Directories and schedules for Board of Managers, 1950 - 1959 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 4)
    - Directories and schedules for Board of Managers, 1960 - 1969 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 5)
    - General Meeting announcements, 1967 - 1979 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 6)
    - Directories and schedules for Board of Managers, 1970 - 1979 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 7)
    - Directories and schedules for Board of Managers, 1980 - 1989 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 8)
    - Duplicate notices, 1838 - 1989 (Offsite-box 97)
  - Subseries I.5: Constitution, Rules, and History, 1842-2008
    The Society periodically produced publications, in addition to the annual reports, that compiled various types of organizational information. These items include governing rules and narrative histories that describe the leadership and activities of the organization over time. They are arranged chronologically.
    - Constitution of the Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York: with a list of its officers and members since 1756, 1842 (Offsite-box SA-8, Volume 48)